Is she having another nightmare?
Now she won't have any scary dreams.
What?!
This is bad! My vision's been taken out.
Was that a demi-human?
What do I do? My sight isn't coming back.
Hey, wait! Please!
I guess I have no choice.
Careful, Uzuma. I think he's
using some kind of spirit art!
Don't worry. It's a spirit art that
detects the od in the area, that's all.
But we should probably assume
that he knows our numbers.
Wait, please!
Are you demi-humans?
If you are, I'd like to talk!
Sara, humans are a dishonorable lot.
I know. But we need to
learn what his aims are.
In that case, we should prepare
for the worst case scenario...
Orphia, Alma, for now, investigate in there.
Understood.
Will do, Sara.
Uzuma, stand by.
Understood.
We shall accept your proposition.
However...
We would rather you not refer to us by
the derogatory epithet "demi-human."
I thank you for your ready consent.
I am called Rio.
With regard to the term I used,
it was not my intent to cause
any offense. I apologize.
Sara!
There's a child of the beast people here!
It looks like spirit arts have
been used to make her sleep!
Uzuma!
I haven't given any orders yet!
He's a marauder who has kidnapped
one of our kin. And...
Watch out! He's using
some kind of spirit art!
What?
It seems like some kind
of healing spirit art.
Hey!
Wait, please!
What's the meaning of this?
We have ascertained that you
have one of our kin in there.
As we have questions about this situation,
we will have you restrained.
This is a misunderstanding!
I was hoping that you would take
her under your protection!
Who would trust a human's...
much less a kidnapper's word?
I didn't kidnap her! Listen to—
What's this?
Your actions are needless.
Seirei Gensouki
Forest of Spirits
Haruto?
You... Who are you?
Me? I... wonder who I am...
You don't know?
No.
But you know about me, don't you?
About you, Haruto?
Haruto is... Haruto.
That's not really an answer.
In that case, why do you know about me?
Because I'm connected to you, Haruto.
Connected to me?
Yes. It's still too soon...
But I belong only to you.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry. It seems our time is up.
Time?
Yes. This is all I can do.
It isn't much, but...
At least you'll have sweet dreams.
Haru-kun?
Haru-kun, wake up!
Mii-chan? Mii-chan!
Mii-chan!
Mii-chan?
Mii-chan—
Are you all right?
Onii-chan!
Latifa...
Why are you crying?
You were gone, Onii-chan!
I don't want that! Don't leave me.
Ow!
Could you please hug me a little more gently?
Huh? Are you hurt? Why?
What's this?
Who did this?
Dear, dear. Can you not walk a little slower?
As I thought.
Human boy, our apologies.
I would like to hear about that young girl.
Can I ask for your cooperation?
More importantly, were you the ones
who did this to Onii-chan?
That's right.
Sir Rio!
I offer my sincerest apologies!
Please, allow us to apologize, too!
Sir Rio, truly, you have
our most sincere apologies!
If the misunderstanding has been resolved,
that's the most important thing.
Uzuma will take full responsibility
for her thoughtless actions.
As will these girls.
Yes, I understand.
But for now, everyone,
please raise your heads.
Orphia, quickly now. Aren't you going
to release his shackles for him?
Y-Yes!
Sir Rio, tomorrow morning,
the Elders will gather
to give you a formal apology.
For tonight, I apologize that all we
can offer is this humble room,
but I hope you and Miss Latifa will
be able to rest well here.
Thank you very much.
We will accept your kind offer.
Good. I have many preparations
that must be made as well.
If you'll allow me, I'll excuse myself.
What is that?
That is the World Tree in which the great
Dryas, a spirit of mighty trees, resides.
Big, isn't it?
Yes.
Heading for that tree is
what brought me this far.
Impressive.
A high-level illusion magic barrier
is erected around that tree.
Without considerable knowledge
of the spirit arts,
one should not be able
to see through it, but...
Really?
Sir Rio, you were not apprenticed under
anyone in the spirit arts, correct?
If what I use is the spirit arts,
then I'm basically self-educated.
I see.
What an outrageous talent you have.
Here we are.
Sir Rio, please sit here.
Well, shall we commence
this council of the Elders?
As we have asked the human boy
to be present on this occasion,
we shall proceed using
the language of humans.
I am one of the Eldest, who bring
together the People of the Spirits
who live in this village.
I am called Syldora.
These two beside me are also of the Eldest.
You already know Ursula.
This dwarf man here is—
I'm Dominic! Nice to meet you, human kid.
As you can see, he has quite
a forthright personality.
I apologize if he causes any offense.
I thank you for your courtesy.
I am pleased to meet you.
I am called Rio.
Please, there is no need for
such deference, Sir Rio!
Considering our misunderstanding
caused such great troubles from our kin,
and that you freed one of our kin
who had been taken into slavery,
we offer you our apologies and
our most heartfelt thanks.
I am honored by your words
of apology and gratitude.
The fault lies also with me, for so
thoughtlessly setting foot in your domain.
Please, raise your heads.
Your generous understanding
makes our hearts ache.
We were hoping we might be able to do
something as a sign of our gratitude, but...
What do you mean?
As we are of different peoples,
it is difficult for us to determine what
would show our gratitude to you, Sir Rio.
I see. In that case...
Would you take Latifa into your care?
Sir Rio, that is our wish.
It is something we should be bowing
our heads and asking of you.
Though you say that...
Please, tell us what you desire.
If it were possible, right now, she...
I think she's grown attached to me, so...
Sir Rio, please, you do not
need to say anything more.
For Latifa's sake, won't you live here
with her in the village for a while?
You wouldn't mind?
We would not.
All of the Eldest here are in agreement.
We would like to ask you to stay.
That's right! Quit being so polite!
You're an even better man than
Ursula made you out to be.
I like you, kid.
Yes, it's just as Ursula and Dominic say.
We intend to take every measure to make sure
living in this village
poses no inconvenience.
If you discover anything you want in the
meantime, please don't hesitate to tell us.
That's right! And it doesn't
have to be an object.
You can even marry one of
the girls from our village!
Dominic, don't get so carried away!
Are you drunk already, you scoundrel?
Sir Rio, that's the way things stand.
All right.
While I live in the village,
then, the spirit arts...
And any knowledge that seems
useful for daily life...
If I could be taught such things...
I see.
Something like that should be
no trouble at all.
Indeed. We'll need to find
an accomplished teacher.
Well, it seems that conversation
has come to a close.
Would it be all right to
move on to my business?
Why... Lady Dryas.
Sir Rio, the personage before you is the
spirit of the World Tree, Lady Dryas.
What? A spirit?
Pleased to meet you, Rio.
Yes, pleased to meet you.
Hmm, just as I thought.
It's very weak, but I sense the
presence of a spirit within you.
Is it... sleeping?
A spirit? Inside me?
Yes. Do you have an idea what it might be?
I think you've probably made a covenant with it.
A covenant? No, I don't have any
particular memory of that...
I see. That's strange.
If you make a covenant with a spirit,
things like an inability
to use magic often occur,
which can be difficult for a human.
Oh. In that case, I've definitely...
There is one person who can't use it.
You're a hindrance who can't even use magic,
but we've prepared a job that even you can do.
Say, would it be all right
if I looked into it a little?
Yes, I'd appreciate that.
Then, please excuse the intrusion.
My! You have an incredible
amount of od hidden inside you!
It looks delicious! Are you really a human?
What?
Did you find something?
More than something, it's...
It's like there's a person-shaped spirit...
sleeping inside you.
A person-shaped spirit?
Hmm, with that reaction, I'd guess you don't
know how rare a person-shaped spirit is.
N-No, I don't.
To put it simply...
Spirits that can take the
shape of a person, like me,
are of the second-highest class or greater.
So one of these person-shaped
spirits sleeps within Sir Rio?
Yes.
The spirits of the highest class,
once called the Six Great Spirits,
all went missing in the Divine-Demon War
over a thousand years ago.
The spirit sleeping within Rio...
may be one of those
high-class spirits, don't you think?
If... If it is a high-class spirit,
would that cause some kind of problem?
I don't think so, but...
Oh, but for the children of the village,
it might be a matter of great importance.
I'm only a spirit of the second-highest class,
and they've gone and
deified me, after all.
That's...
What does that mean?
It would mean that
we must once again rethink the manner
in which we treat you, Sir Rio.
What?
To put it plainly, Sir Rio,
we would discuss whether it would
be better to treat you as a saint.
A... saint?
Don't worry about the details!
Just think of it getting extra-special
treatment while you're in our village.
I'll do that, then.
Onii-chan!
Welcome home, Sir Rio.
Onii-chan! This house is amazing!
It has an open-air bath!
A kitchen!
A beautiful view.
Yes.
It's delicious!
Is that...
This?
Oryza grains are threshed to remove
the hulls, then cooked with saffron.
Oryza?
Yes.
It's a foodstuff that originated
in the Yagumo region.
Do you not have it in the Strahl region?
No.
That's right! They have rice here!
Rice! Rice!
What are you saying? You're so strange.
But, I mean, it's okome!
Um... I was wondering, Sir Rio,
which rooms would you like us to sleep in?
I'm sorry?
Huh? Um... The Eldest...
Lady Ursula didn't mention anything to you?
About what?
The three of us are to live here in this
house and look after both of you, Sir Rio.
What?
All of you are going to live here, too?
Yes. Would you rather we didn't?
I-I don't know...
It's just...
Sir Rio, forgive the intrusion.
Mistress Ursula...
Regarding Sara and the others
living here with you,
I humbly ask your permission.
Though you say that...
Won't it cause problems for them?
Living with a human like me...
That's precisely why they should.
Talk of you and Latifa has already
spread among the villagers.
If the higher-ups in the village approach
you as they might some kind of abscess,
that would be far worse.
I see.
This is for Latifa's sake, too.
Someone besides you who can
be her guardian, her friend...
She needs someone who will
stay by her side, correct?
That is true, but...
Then we shall consider
the matter settled.
Oh, well, I am grateful for
what it means for Latifa.
As long as we aren't imposing
on Miss Sara and the others.
That's wonderful, isn't it, everyone?
Thank you so much, Sir Rio!
Not at all. It is I who
should be thanking you.
I will be counting on you from now on.
Of course, Sir Rio!
Oh... and...
I would be grateful if you
would stop using "sir" with me.
Well, in that case...
Would Master Rio be acceptable?
Yes, that will be fine. Please go with that!
We will now begin the rites
for the Grand Spirit Festival!
Here, under the profound
grace of the great spirits,
we hope that blessings
and divine protection
shall forever accompany us, the People
of the Spirits, on the path we travel.
Lady Dryas!
Now, then, I believe it's
about time to descend.
Let's go.
Y-Yes, sir!
A-Are we going in there?
Yes.
Around this time, the master of that
cave will be out looking for food.
It won't be returning for a while,
so please, don't worry.
You wait here.
Well done in making it this far in your
effort to join the Celestial Lion Brigade.
If you clear this next test,
you will receive permission to officially
join the brigade as a member.
Sir!
Oh, good! Now all that's left is to get back.
M-Master Reiss, what is that?
It's obvious, isn't it? It's an egg.
Wh-What kind of egg?
What's this? Would you really like to know?
Oh! Um... No!
We are considering what, after griffins,
might be used to newly augment
the Celestial Lion Brigade's military strength.
What?
You will carry this egg, please.
I must manage the griffin, after all.
Y-Yes, sir.
Well then, let us return.
The parent won't get angry and come
to take back the egg... right?
The distance between here and the Strahl
region is considerable, is it not?
That's true...
Next Time
Festival Night
"Festival Night."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
Beast-eared.
By Minazuki Futago
Hello
Elf.
Yes
Dwarf...
probably.
Yup
Fantasy
enthusiasts
probably love
this to bits.
HISS
Latifa,
calm
down